# ZOE GENEVIEVE LEBLANC

DIGITAL HUMANITIES DEVELOPER & HISTORIAN

## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am currently a Digital Humanities Developer at the Scholars' Lab at the University of Virginia and also completing my doctorate in History at Vanderbilt University. I am interested in opportunities where I can bridge my knowledge of software development and data science with my experience in digital humanities research. I am passionate about developing best practices for collaboration, and new methods for researchers to create and share knowledge.

# SELECTED EXPERIENCE

Digital Humanities Developer, Scholars Lab, University of Virginia, 08/2017-Present Responsible for leading the R&D team's web development projects, which includes evaluating technology stacks and project planning. Current projects include a project management app built on a graph database, and the rebuilding of Neatline in React to work with any backend. Also responsible for leading workshops on web development, network analysis, and natural language processing, and providing consultations and training to the UVA community.

#### Data Developer, Aspire Health, 03/2017-07/2017

Responsible for coordinating with the data development team to find solutions for increasing patient enrollment. Built patient enrollment app to help analyze trends in patient acquisition and assist doctors in recommending patients to service. Also built mapping app to visualize trends in market data and predict future areas of growth. Worked in React, Redux, Immutable.JS, Elixir and Postgres.

Web Designer and Office Manager, Contemporary Computers, 12/2010-08/2011 Designed business plan and websites for computer repair store. Learned foundations of computer hardware, front-end web development, and website design.

## SELECTED PROJECTS

#### Kraken App, 2018-Present

Project Management app built in D3.js, React, Flask, and Neo4j to help the Scholars' Lab track people, projects, and events. View: www.github.com/scholarslab/kraken\_app

## Scholars' Lab Website, 2017-Present

Website redesign of the Scholars' Lab site into Jekyll. Focused on integrating Ruby and Javscript for a Lunr search engine and custom dynamic templates. View: www.github.com/scholarslab/scholarslab.org

# Image Lucida, 2017-Present

Image annotation and analysis web app built in Django, Angular, and Postgres, using OCR APIs and computer vision segmentation to help researchers analyze and extract large image datasets from archival sources. Beta-testing on dissertation research. View: www.github.com/ZoeLeBlanc/image\_lucida

#### Digital Humanities Projects from Dissertation, 2016-Present

Two projects: "Dispatches from Cairo" a text analysis project of Western diplomatic dispatches from Cairo and "Depictions of Decolonization" an image analysis project of anti-colonial newspapers and magazines, using word embeddings, topic modeling, computer vision algorithms and networks analysis. View: zoeleblanc.com/projects/

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in History, Vanderbilt University, 05/2014- Defense Fall 2018
Full Stack Web Develoopment Bootcamp, Nashville Software School, 07/2016-03/2017
M.A. in History, Vanderbilt University, 09/2011-04/2014

zgleblanc@gmail.com zoeleblanc.com 615.810.6485 Charlottesville, VA

# **SOCIAL**

TWITTER/ Zoe\_LeBlanc

GITHUB/ ZoeLeBlanc

in LINKEDIN/ in/zoe-leblanc

# **SKILLS**

Web app development: Python, Django, Flask, SQL, Postgres, Neo4j, Javascript, JQuery, Angular, React, Redux, Elixir, Ruby, Jekyll, CSS, Sass, HTML, Webpack, Grunt, Browserify, Firebase, Agile, Unit Testing, Mocha, Chai

Data analysis:
Pandas, R, D3.js,
Jupyter Notebooks,
Natural Language Processing,
Computer Vision,
Network Analysis

Languages:

Fluent in French, advanced reading and writing in Arabic

## **SELECTED AWARDS**

Vanderbilt Digital Humanities Fellowship, 2016-2017

Canadian Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council Dissertation Award, 2014-2016

Nashville Software School Tuition Scholarship & Catalyst Award 2017

Vanderbilt Institute of Digital Learning Graduate Fellowship, 2014-2015

HASTAC Scholar, Vanderbilt Center for Teaching, 2012-2013

Vanderbilt Graduate Fellowship, 2011-2017

Honours Bachelor of Arts with High Distinction, Trinity College, University of Toronto, 09/2006-06/2010